Ethan Mu

Address: 15 Loughros Place Pinehill NorthShore

Blogs: www.politecode.com / https://chenmu1.github.io/

Email: ethan.mu@politecode.com

Mobile: 021 255 5719

Summary

I am a web developer with a passion for creating websites that put contents and users first. Besides having a solid foundation in design principles, I constantly read about web development and the technologies required to work with it. I enjoy working in a team and producing quality software in a high-pressure working environment.

Technical Expertise

.NET Framework: C#, .NET Framework, ASP.NET MVC
Web Technologies: HTML5/ JavaScript/ CSS/, AJAX, jQuery

Databases: MS SQL Server, Stored procedure, Functions and Performance tuning

Tools: Visual Studio 2017, Visual Studio Code, TFS, Fiddler, Postman

Professional Experience

MVP Studio (NZ) Web Developer (Intern) July 2017 – October 2017

MVP Studio was created to fill a gap in the software development industry in New Zealand. It provides developer assistance and technical support to start-up small businesses in New Zealand and Australia. Website: http://www.mvp.studio/

Project Billion (a platform that connects apprentices, trainers and investors)

Technology used: C# / ASP.NET MVC / MVVM / HTML5 / JavaScript / JQuery / Bootstrap / SQL Server / TFS

Responsibilities:

- Designed a CV management system that allows participants to upload CVs to be reviewed by trainers
- Allowed participants to view CV versions along with its review comments and modified CV contents.
- Enabled participants to modify their profile contact details and link their profile with social media and online community accounts
- Worked in an Agile development team

AIMY PLUS (NZ) Web Developer (Intern) March 2017 – July 2017

Aimy Plus is a cloud-based software solution. It provides services for child programme management, real-time booking, and financial transactions. It has been rolled out to NZ, Canada, Ireland, and the UK Website: http://www.aimyplus.com/

Project FamBam (a social media platform for parents to interact with their children activity)

Technology used: C# / ASP.NET MVC / MVVM / HTML5 / JavaScript / JQuery / Bootstrap / SQL Server / SSRS / Web API / RESTful web service / TFS

Responsibilities:

- Designed REST APIs that allow sophisticated and effective application integration for activity providers
- Worked in an agile development environment. Participated in creating programs for activity providers
- Developed dynamic and interactive web pages, modules and applications for activity providers. Allowed the providers to manage all program details.

Personal Project

 Self-made a Bootstrap website homepage(the Warehouse) with flexible options for portfolios and businesses

https://github.com/ChenMu1/Creative

 A react-redux powered single page admin dashboard. Used progressive web application pattern, highly optimized for your next react application.

https://github.com/ChenMu1/Amazing-React-App

Interests

I enjoy playing puzzles with family and friends during my spare time. I also enjoy cooking. Furthermore, I have a keen interest in computer related products, drawing and Artificial intelligence.

Education

Massey University (2013 - 2017)

Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Major: Computer Science Minor: Mathematics
 Favourite courses: Artificial Intelligence and Calculus

Grade	Major Papers
B+	Web Development
В	Algorithms and Data Structures
	Computer Architecture
	 Concurrent Programming and Operating Systems
B-	Networks, Security and the Internet

	Minor papers
А	Calculus
B+	Differential Equations
B-	Linear Algebra

Referrals

Available on request